《夺宝奇兵：法柜奇兵》
那些人就在附近
The Hovitos are near.
毒药还很新鲜  是三天前放的
The poison is still fresh, three days.
他们正在跟踪我们
They're following us.
如果他们知道我们在这  早就干掉我们了
If they knew we were here, they would've killed us already.
(1936年  南美洲)
就是这里了
This is it.
费雷斯就是死在这里的
This is where Forrestal cashed in.
- 他是你的朋友？ - 不 是一个对手
- A friend of yours? -  A competitor.
他非常棒
He was good.
他非常非常不错
He was very, very good.
先生  没有人能活着从这出来
Senor, nobody's come out of there alive
求您了…
Please...
先生…
Senor.
停
Stop.
别站在亮处
Stay out of the light.
真可怜
Forrestal.
快点  这里没有什么好怕的
Let us hurry. There is nothing to fear here.
这就是我所害怕的
That's what scares me.
呆在这里
Stay here.
恭敬不如从命
If you insist, senor.
把鞭子扔过来
Give me the whip.
把头像给我
Throw me the idol.
没有时间争论了
No time to argue.
把头像给我  我才给你鞭子
Throw me the idol, I throw you the whip.
把鞭子给我!
Give me the whip!
再见了  先生
Adios, senor.
再见了  萨提泊
Adios, Satipo.
琼斯博士
Dr. Jones.
我们再次看到  你在这里拿走的任何东西
Again we see there is nothing you can possess
都能被我夺走
which I cannot take away.
而你认为我已经放弃了
And you thought I had given up.
你选错朋友了 这次会搭上你的性命
You chose the wrong friends. This time, it will cost you.
可惜那些人的想法和我不一样  拜尔劳库
Too bad the Hovitos don't know you the way I do, Belloq.
是的  太可惜了
Yes, too bad.
只要你能说他们的语言 你就能指挥他们
You could warn them, if only you spoke Hovitos.
杰克!  发动引擎!
Jock! Start the engines!
准备起飞!
Get it up!
杰克  发动引擎!
Jock, the engines!
发动引擎!  杰克!
Start the engines, Jock!
飞机里有条大蛇  杰克!
There's a big snake in the plane, Jock!
噢  那只是我的宠物蛇雷吉!
Oh, that's just my pet snake Reggie!
我讨厌蛇  杰克!
I hate snakes, Jock!
我讨厌它们!
I hate 'em!
少来了!  拿出点勇气好吗？
Come on! Show a little backbone, will ya?
"奈欧"意思是"新"
"Neo" meaning "new"...
"埃泰克"意思是"石头"
and "Lithic"... "L-T-H"...meaning "stone".
好了  我们再谈谈这个陵墓
All right, let's get back to this site:
图坦卡门墓  靠近帝王谷
Turkdean Barrow, near Hazelton.
它有一条中央通道和三个主墓室…
Contains a central passage and three chambers, or cysts...
…它并没有被盗墓者破坏  也就是说
...don't confuse that with robbing, in which case we mean
没有被拿走里面的东西
the removal of the contents of the barrow.
这个陵墓也证实了…
This site also demonstrates...
…它是考古学中最大的危险之一…
...one of the great dangers of archeology,
不是关于人身安全  尽管有时会出这种事
not to life and limb, although that does sometimes take place.
现在  我们来谈谈民俗
No, I'm talking about folklore.
在这个例子中  本地人都坚持认为
In this case, local tradition held
这里埋着一个金棺材
that there was a golden coffin buried at the site,
因此到那个地方挖掘
and this accounts for the holes dug all over the barrow
可是没有找到任何东西
and the generally poor condition of the find.
不过  第三室还没有被动过
However, chamber three was undisturbed,
而在这个没有被动过的墓室  我们可以找到殉葬品
and the undisturbed chamber and the grave goods
在另一个地方  嗯…
that were found in another, uh...
在这里  给我们…
in the area, give us a r...
嗯…
Uh...
…一个理由去…这就是我们最近得到的消息
...reason to da... to, uh, to-to date this,
呃  这个以前就知道了
uh, find as we have.
嗯…
Um...
还有问题吗？
Any questions, then?
没有问题了？那好  今天到此为止
No? Okay, that's it for the day, then.
嗯  别忘了…
Um, don't forget...
下次我们讲第四章和第五章
Michaelson, chapters four and five for next time.
我周四会呆在我的办公室  而不是周三
And I will be in my office on Thursday, but not Wednesday.
我已经得手了  马库斯
I had it, Marcus.
我已经把它弄到手了
I had it in my hand.
- 什么？ - 猜猜
- What happened? -  Guess.
- 拜尔劳库？ - 你要不要听？
- Belloq?    -  You want to hear about it?
一点也不想
Not at all.
我清楚你为博物馆所作的每件事情
I'm sure everything you do for the museum
都符合国际保护文物条约
conforms to the International Treaty for the Protection of Antiquities.
它很漂亮  马库斯
It's beautiful, Marcus.
我能得到它  我一切都计划好了
I can get it. I got it all figured out.
只有一个地方可供他卖掉它: 马拉克奇
There's only one place he can sell it: Marrakech.
我需要2000美元
I need $2,000. Look...
伙计  听着
Listen to me, old boy.
我带了一些人来见你
I brought some people to see you.
看
Look.
我这有些东西
I got these pieces.
都是好东西  马库斯
They're good pieces, Marcus.
- 看  - 印第安纳…
- Look.   -  Indiana...
不错  博物馆会买下它们的  而且一般不会问什么
Yes, the museum will buy them, as usual, no questions asked.
- 是啊  他们很好说话   - 至少它们值
- Yes, they are nice. -  They're worth at least
一张去马拉克奇的机票
the price of a ticket to Marrakech.
不过我带来的人比较重要
But the people I brought are important,
- 他们在等你  - 什么人？
- and they're waiting. -  What people?
军方情报人员
Army Intelligence.
他们比我还早知道你要来
They knew you were coming before I did.
他们似乎无所不知
Seem to know everything.
他们不会告诉我他们的目的
They wouldn't tell me what they want.
那么  我为什么要见他们呢？
Well, what do I want to see them for?
我怎么了？有麻烦吗？
What am I, in trouble?
是的  琼斯博士
Yes, Dr. Jones,
我们听了很多关于你的事情
we've heard a great deal about you.
是吗？
Have you?
嗯  考古学教授
Uh, professor of archeology,
超自然学专家
expert on the occult,
嗯  还有什么？
and, uh, how does one say it?
珍贵文物收集者
Obtainer of rare antiquities.
就是这样子的
That's one way of saying it.
你为什么不坐下？这样会舒服一点
Why don't you sit down? You'll be more comfortable.
-  谢谢  -  谢谢
- Oh, thank you. -  Thank you.
的确  你是个多才多艺的人
Yes, you're a man of many talents.
你在芝加哥大学的
Now, you studied under Professor Ravenwood
瑞文伍德教授那里学习过
at the University of Chicago.
是的
Yes, I did.
你不知道他现在的行踪吗？
You have no idea of his present whereabouts?
嗯… 只是传言
Uh... well, just rumors, really.
我想是在亚洲的某个地方
Somewhere in Asia, I think.
我有十年没和他通话了
I haven't really spoken to him for ten years.
我们是朋友  不过…
We were friends, but, uh...
有些小争吵
had a bit of a falling out, I'm afraid.
嗯
Mmm.
琼斯博士  现在  你必须清楚
Dr. Jones, now, you must understand
这个属于绝密  知道吗？
that this is all strictly confidential, eh?
我清楚
I understand.
嗯…
Uh...
昨天下午  我们欧洲的组织
Yesterday afternoon, our European sections
截获一份… 一份德国人的文件
intercepted a... a German communique
是从开罗送到柏林的
that was sent from Cairo to Berlin.
- 现在  去开罗…  - 看  这两年多
- Now, to Cairo...   -  See, over the last two years,
纳粹有支考古队
the Nazis have had teams of archeologists
满世界转悠  寻找各种宗教文物
running around the world looking for all kinds of religious artifacts.
希特勒迷上了这事
Hitler's a nut on the subject.
他很狂热
He's crazy.
他对超自然力量很着迷
He's obsessed with the occult.
因此  现在  很明显
And, right now, apparently,
有一支德国考古挖掘队
there's some kind of German archeological dig
正去往开罗城外的沙漠
going on in the desert outside of Cairo.
我们现在得到一些情报
Now, we've got some information here,
不过我们看不明白  也许你能
but we can't make anything out of it, and maybe you can.
"塔尼斯项目正在进行中"
"Tanis development proceeding.
"得到美国瑞文伍德教授的合作"
"Acquire headpiece, Staff of Ra. Abner Ravenwood, U.S."
纳粹已经发现了塔尼斯
The Nazis have discovered Tanis.
塔尼斯对你又意味着什么？
Just what does that mean to you, uh, Tanis?
它…
Well, it...
塔尼斯城可能就是一处保存有失落的法柜的地方
The city of Tanis is one of the possible resting places of the Lost Ark.
失落的法柜？
The Lost Ark?
是的  就是圣经约柜
Yeah, the Ark of the Covenant.
希伯来人用来保存十戒的箱子
The chest the Hebrews used to carry around the Ten Commandments.
"戒律"？什么意思？
What do you mean, "commandments"?
你说的是十戒？
You talking about the Ten Commandments?
是的  真正的十戒
Yes, the actual Ten Commandments.
最初刻在石碑上的十戒
The original stone tablets
就是摩西从山上带下来又打破了的石碑
that Moses brought down out of Mount Horeb and smashed,
你们是否相信这种事
if you believe in that sort of thing.
你们这些家伙不去主日学校吗？
Any of you guys ever go to Sunday school?
- 嗯  我…  - 哦  看
- Well, I...   -  Oh, look.
希伯来人把这些打破的石碑
The Hebrews took the broken pieces
放入法柜  当他们在伽南定居后
and put them in the Ark. When they settled in Canaan,
他们把法柜安置在一个叫所罗门神庙的地方
they put the Ark in a place called the Temple of Solomon.
在耶路撒冷
In Jerusalem.
在那它放了很多年
Where it stayed for many years.
直到突然不翼而飞
Until, all of a sudden, whoosh, it's gone.
去哪里了？
Where?
没有人知道去哪里了  也没人知道是什么时候
Well, nobody knows where or when.
然而  一个埃及法老
However, an Egyptian pharaoh...
- 斯沙克  - 是的
- Shishak.   -  Yes.
…大概在公元前980年左右  侵入耶路撒冷
...Invaded the city of Jerusalem right about 980 BC,
他可能把法柜拿回塔尼斯城
and he may have taken the Ark back to the city of Tanis
而且藏在一个秘密的墓室
and hidden it in a secret chamber
据说叫灵魂井
called the Well of Souls.
秘密的墓室？
Secret chamber?
可是  就在法老回到埃及一年后
However, about a year after the pharaoh would return to Egypt,
塔尼斯城消失在沙漠中
the city of Tanis was consumed by the desert
被持续了一整年的沙尘暴淹没了
in a sandstorm which lasted a whole year.
被上帝之怒完全抹掉了
Wiped clean by the wrath of God.
嗯
Uh-huh.
显然  我们找对了人
Obviously, we've come to the right men.
两位好像对塔尼斯都很了解
Now you seem to know, uh, all about this Tanis, then.
不  不  不见得
No, no, not really.
瑞文伍德才是真正的专家
Ravenwood is the real expert.
他是第一个对塔尼斯有过认真研究的人
Abner did the first serious work on Tanis.
收集了一些关于它衰落的东西
Collected some of its relics.
他真的好像被它给迷住了
It was his obsession, really.
不过他从来没有找到这个城市
But he never found the city.
坦率地说  我们对瑞文伍德先生有点怀疑
Frankly, we're somewhat suspicious of Mr. Ravenwood.
在一份纳粹的秘密电报中
An American being mentioned so prominently
很明显地提到他的名字
in a secret Nazi cable.
胡说  瑞文伍德不是纳粹
Oh, rubbish. Ravenwood's no Nazi.
那么纳粹想要他做什么呢？
Well, what do the Nazis want him for, then?
显然  纳粹正在寻找一个雷之权杖
Well, obviously, the Nazis are looking for the headpiece to the Staff of Ra
而他们以为这东西在阿伯奈手上
and they think Abner's got it.
到底是什么样的东西？
What exactly is a headpiece to the Staff of Ra?
是一个手杖
Well, the staff is just a stick...
这么大
I don't know, about this big,
没有人确切知道它的高度
nobody really knows for sure how high...
以及它的…它的…呃
And it's... it's, uh... it's capped
它被一个精心制作的头盔包起来了…
with an elaborate headpiece...
它形状像太阳  中间有块水晶
in the shape of the sun, with a crystal in the center.
而你所做的就是
And what you did was
把这个东西带到塔尼斯里面的一个特别房间
you take the staff to a special room in Tanis...
地上有一个这城市的缩微模型
A map room with a miniature of the city all laid out on the floor,
如果你在一天中的某个特定时刻
and if you put the staff in a certain place,
把这东西放在某个特定的地点 太阳从这边照过来
at a certain time of day, the sun shone through here
而从这里发出一簇光线  到地上这点…
and made a beam that came down on the floor here...
它就会指出这个庙的确切方位
and gave you the exact location of the Well of the Souls.
法柜就在那里  对吧？
Where the Ark of the Covenant was kept, right?
那就是纳粹正在找的东西
Which is exactly what the Nazis are looking for.
这个法柜看起来什么样子？
What does this Ark look like?
这里有它的一张图
There's a picture of it right here.
就是它
That's it.
天呐
Good God.
没错  那正是希伯来人的想法
Yes, that's just what the Hebrews thought.
这些发射出来的又是什么？
now, what's that supposed to be coming out of there?
光…
Lightning...
火…
fire...
是上帝的能力
power of God or something.
我开始明白了
I'm beginning to understand
希特勒对这个感兴趣
Hitler's interest in this.
对
Oh, yes.
圣经上提过这法柜能移动山脉
The Bible speaks of the Ark leveling mountains,
还能摧毁它经过的每个地方
and laying waste to entire regions.
拥有法柜的军队...
An army which carries the Ark before it...
是无敌的
is invincible.
你办到了  对吧？
You did it, didn't you?
他们想让你去找它
They want you to go for it.
哦  马库斯!
Oh, Marcus!
他们想让你抢在纳粹前头拿到它
They want you to get a hold of the Ark before the Nazis do
为此  他们准备了丰厚的报酬
and they're prepared to pay handsomely for it.
那博物馆呢？
And the museum?
我们办妥后  博物馆就得到法柜吗？
The museum gets the Ark when we're finished?
是的
Oh, yes.
哦…
Oh...
这个法柜很重要
The Ark of the Covenant.
没有什么东西像它那么重要
Nothing else has come close.
它象征万物
That thing represents everything
它在考古学中地位超然
we got into archeology for in the first place.
嗯!
Mmm!
你知道  要是在五年前  我会自己去找的
You know, five years ago, I would've gone after it myself.
我有点嫉妒你了
I'm really rather envious.
我需要先找到阿伯奈
I've got to locate Abner.
我想我知道从哪里着手
I think I know where to start.
她还和他在一起吗？
Suppose she'll still be with him?
也许吧  不过…
Possibly, but...
现在可不是想玛丽安的时候
Marion's the least of your worries right now,
相信我  印第
believe me, Indy.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我是说  3000年来
Well, I mean that for nearly 3,000 years,
人们一直在寻找法柜
man has been searching for the Lost Ark.
这点不容忽视
Not something to be taken lightly.
没有人知道它的秘密
No one knows its secrets.
你从未接触过它
It's like nothing you've ever gone after before.
哦  马库斯
Oh, Marcus.
你想做什么？吓我么？
What are you trying to do, scare me?
你的口气像我老妈
You sound like my mother.
我们认识很久了
We've known each other for a long time.
我不相信魔法 这有太多迷信成分
I don't believe in magic, a lot of superstitious hocus-pocus.
我要去寻找的是
I'm going after a find
你正在谈论的
of incredible historical significance.
有着重要历史意义的东西
You're talking about the bogeyman.
而且  你知道我是一个好奇心很强的人
Besides, you know what a cautious fellow I am.
很高兴再见到你  琼斯博士
Nice to see you again, Dr. Jones.
谢谢
Thank you.
(尼泊尔)
嘘…嘘…
Shh... shh...
嘘…
Shh...
让他干!  让他干!
Give him space! Give him space!
再来一杯  雷甘!
Go on, Regan!
嘘!  嘘!
Shh! Shh!
嘘!  嘘!  嘘!
Shh! Shh! Shh!
你好  玛丽安
Hello, Marion.
印第安纳·琼斯
Indiana Jones.
我知道  总有一天
Always knew, someday,
你会回来找我
you'd come walking back through my door.
我从未怀疑这点
I never doubted that.
这无法避免
Something made it inevitable.
你来尼泊尔做什么？
So, what are you doing here in Nepal?
我需要你父亲收集的一样东西
I need one of the pieces your father collected.
这十年中  我学会了恨你
I learned to hate you in the last ten years.
我从未想伤害你
I never meant to hurt you.
那时我还是一个小孩
I was a child.
我坠入爱河
I was in love.
这本来不对  而你也知道这点
It was wrong and you knew it!
你知道你在做什么
You knew what you were doing.
现在我知道了  这是我的地方
Now I do! This is my place.
你滚!
Get out!
事情已经发生了
I did what I did.
你不一定要为此感到高兴
You don't have to be happy about it,
不过现在也许我们能互相帮助
but maybe we could help each other out now.
我需要你父亲收集的一样东西
I need one of the pieces your father collected.
青铜做的  大概这么大
Bronze piece, about this size,
中间有个洞  里面有块水晶
with a hole in it, off-center, with a crystal.
你知道我说的是什么吗？
You know the one I mean?
知道
Yeah.
我知道有这个东西
I know it.
阿伯奈在哪？
Where's Abner?
阿伯奈已经死了
Abner's dead.
玛丽安  对不起
Marion, I'm sorry.
你知道你的所作所为对我意味着什么吗？
Do you know what you did to me, to my life?
我只能说  我非常抱歉
I can only say I'm sorry so many times.
好吧  再说一遍
Well, say it again, anyway.
对不起
Sorry.
够了  每个人都说对不起
Yeah, everybody's sorry.
阿伯奈说对不起  是因为他拖着我满世界跑
Abner was sorry for dragging me all over this earth
寻找他那些无用的东西
looking for his little bits of junk.
我很难过  现在还困在这个破酒吧
I'm sorry to still be stuck in this dive.
每个人都有一些事要说对不起
Everybody's sorry for something.
那是一个价值连城的青铜奖章
It's a worthless bronze medallion, Marion.
你能交给我吗？
You going to give it to me?
有可能
Maybe.
我不知道它在哪里
I don't know where it is.
也许你能找到它
Well, maybe you could find it.
我给你3000
3,000 bucks.
你又来了  可我不吃这一套
Well, that will get me back, but not in style.
等我们到了美国  我再另给你2000
I can get you another two when we get to the States.
这很重要  玛丽安
It's important, Marion.
相信我
Trust me.
你知道我要的是哪一块？
You know the piece I mean?
你知道它在哪里？
Do you know where it is?
明天再来
Come back tomorrow.
为什么？
Why?
因为我这样吩咐了  这就是原因
Because I said so, that's why.
明天见  印第安纳·琼斯
See you tomorrow, Indiana Jones.
晚安  小姐
Good evening, Fraulein.
酒吧已经关门了
The bar's closed.
我们…我们…
We... We are...
不是来喝酒的
not thirsty.
你们想要什么？
What do you want?
和你的朋友琼斯博士想要的东西一样
The same thing your friend Dr. Jones wanted.
他肯定会告诉你这里将有
Surely he told you there would be
另外一些有趣的派对
other interested parties.
他一定忘了
Must've slipped his mind.
这个人…很坏
The man is... nefarious.
为你着想  我希望他还没有得到它
I hope, for your sake, he has not yet acquired it.
你愿意出更高的价吗？
Why, are you willing to offer more?
噢  当然
Oh, almost certainly.
还在你手上吗？
Do you still have it?
不在
No.
不过我知道它在哪里
But I know where it is.
嗨  你们来喝一杯如何？
Hey, how about a drink for you and your men?
你的火已经熄了
Your fire is dying here.
你为什么不现在就告诉我那个东西在哪里呢？
Why don't you tell me where the piece is right now?
听我说  马可先生…
Listen, Herr Mac...
我不知道你一向和什么人打交道
I don't know what kind of people you're used to dealing with,
但是没有人能在我的地盘吩咐我该做什么
but nobody tells me what to do in my place.
瑞文伍德小姐
Fraulein Ravenwood,
让我给你瞧瞧我的做事风格
let me show you what I am used to.
把你的手拿开
Take your hands off me!
把你的手拿开!
Take your lousy hands off!
等一下
Wait a minute.
我…我可以谈谈吗？
Wait, I... I can be reasonable.
已经晚了
That time is passed.
你不必这样子
You don't need that.
等等…
Wait...
我会全告诉你
I'll tell you everything.
是的  我知道你会
Yes, I know you will.
让她走
Let her go.
威士忌
Whiskey.
打死他们
Shoot them.
两个都打死
Shoot them both.
我的徽章!
My medallion!
琼斯  至少你还没忘记
Well, Jones, at least you haven't forgotten
怎样讨好女人
how to show a lady a good time!
你很了不起
Boy, you're something!
我要告诉你
Yeah, I'll tell you what.
在我没拿到五千美元以前
Until I get back my $5,000,
你会得到你想象不到的东西
you're going to get more than you bargained for.
我是你的最佳损友
I'm your goddamn partner!
(开罗)
开罗  充满活力的城市
Cairo, city of the living.
一座人间天堂
A paradise on earth.
安静!
Silence!
你们怎么这样吵？
Why do you forget yourselves?
这是什么？
What is this?
这畜生从哪里钻出来的？
Where did this animal come from?
哦…哦  不
Oh... oh, no.
真可爱
Cute.
多可爱的小家伙
What an adorable creature.
那他就可以呆在我们家
Then it shall be welcome in our house.
不要  不要因为我把它留下
Oh, well, no, you don't have to keep it here just because of me.
我知道德国人会雇你的  萨拉
I knew the Germans would hire you, Sallah.
你是埃及最好的矿工
You're the best digger in Egypt.
我的效劳对他们无关轻重
My services are entirely inconsequential to them.
他们雇了开罗所有的矿工
They've hired or shanghaied every digger in Cairo.
挖掘量很大
The excavation is enormous.
他们只雇强壮的人  而且工钱很少
They hire only strong backs and they pay pennies for them.
似乎又回到了古埃及
It's as if the pharaohs had returned.
他们什么时候找到了地图室？
When did they find the map room?
3天前
Three days ago.
他们中没有什么人才
They have not one brain among them.
除了一个
Except one.
他非常聪明  是一个法国的考古家
He is very clever. He's a French archeologist.
他叫什么名字？
What's his name?
他们叫他"拜尔劳斯"
They call him "Bellosh."
拜尔劳库  拜尔劳库
Belloq. Belloq.
德国人已经比我们领先了
The Germans have a great advantage over us.
他们快要发现灵井了
They are near to discovering the Well of Souls.
他们没有这个  找不到灵井
Well, they're not going to find it without this.
谁能给我们讲讲这些记号
Who can tell us about these markings?
也许我认识个人能帮我们
Perhaps a man I know can help us.
印第…
Indy...
有些东西在困扰着我
there is something that troubles me.
什么？
What is it?
法柜
The Ark.
如果在这里  在塔尼斯
If it is there, at Tanis,
那么人们不该去骚扰它
then it is something that man was not meant to disturb.
它常伴随着死亡
Death has always surrounded it.
它不属于地球
It is not of this earth.
我们要这猴子吗？
Do we need the monkey, huh?
琼斯  我很惊讶
I'm surprised at you, Jones,
你这样谈论我们的孩子
talking that way about our baby.
他继承了你的容貌
He's got your looks, too.
还有你的智慧
And your brains.
啊!
Oops!
我注意到了
I noticed that.
它很古灵精怪
She's a smart little thing. Smart.
嗨!
Hey!
你去哪儿？
Hey, where you going?
她没事  吃个枣子吧
She'll be all right. Have a date.
快来  快来
Come on. Come on.
- 好的…  - 玛丽安
- Okay... -  Marion.
这是什么？
What's this?
枣子
It's a date.
你吃吧
You eat 'em.
你怎么没找个好女孩安定下来？
How come you haven't found some nice girl to settle down with,
像你的朋友萨拉那样
raise eight or nine kids, like your friend Sallah?
谁说我没有？
Who says I haven't?
我说的
I do.
老爸早就料到你会这样
Dad had you figured a long time ago.
他说你是一个混球
He said you were a bum.
他已经说得很客气了
Oh, he's being generous.
你是他最有天分的学生
The most gifted bum he ever trained.
你知道  他待你象亲生儿子一样
You know, he loved you like a son.
你和他疏远代价很大
Took a hell of a lot for you to alienate him.
并不多  就是你
Not much, just you.
玛丽安  离开这里
Marion, get out of here!
闪开
Duck!
好
Right.
嘘!  嘘!
Shh! Shh!
玛丽安!
Marion!
救救我  在这里  印第!
Help! Over here, Indy!
让开!
Get out of the way!
Move! Move it!
救救我!
Help me!
你们不能这样对我!
You can't do this to me!
我是美国人!
I'm an American!
印第!
Indy!
印第安纳·琼斯
Indiana Jones!
救救我  琼斯!
Help me, Jones!
琼斯!
Jones!
玛丽安!
Marion!
印第!
Indy!
玛丽安…
Marion...
琼斯博士
Dr. Jones.
你在找我吗？
You looking for me?
拜尔劳库
Belloq.
下午好  琼斯博士
Good afternoon, Dr. Jones.
我应该现在就杀了你
I ought to kill you right now.
这地方杀人太显眼了吧
Not a very private place for a murder.
这些阿拉伯人才不管我们互相厮杀呢
Well, these Arabs don't care if we kill each other.
他们不会管闲事的
They're not going to interfere in our business.
不是我想把那女孩拉进来的
It was not I who brought the girl into this business.
要是不想摔倒  请先坐下来
Please, sit down before you fall down.
我们至少可以像文明人处事
We can at least behave like civilized people.
我看到你还是交那些朋友
I see your taste in friends remains consistent.
我们多年的交情  这样的结局真怪
How odd that it should end this way for us,
尤其是经历了这么多冒险之后
after so many stimulating encounters.
我几乎有点遗憾
I almost regret it.
我哪里再去找个这样旗鼓相当的对手
Where shall I find a new adversary so close to my own level?
试试本地的下水道
Try the local sewer.
你我有很多相似的地方
You and I are very much alike.
考古就是我们的信仰
Archeology is our religion,
但我们的信仰都不纯
yet we have both fallen from the purer faith.
我们的手法并无很大的不同
Our methods have not differed as much as you pretend.
我很像你
I am a shadowy reflection of you.
说你像我也易如反掌
It would take only a nudge to make you like me,
只要把你我换位
to push you out of the light.
你现在越来越胡说了
Now you're getting nasty.
你知道这是事实
You know it's true.
真不错
How nice.
看这个
Look at this.
这不值钱
It's worthless.
花十块钱就能从街头小贩手中买到
Ten dollars from a vendor in the street.
但我把它埋在沙里经过一千年后
But I take it, I bury it in the sand for a thousand years,
它就变得像法柜那样价值连城
it becomes priceless... Like the Ark.
人类会为了它残杀
Men will kill for it.
就像你和我一样
Men like you and me.
你老板弗郁尔先生呢？
What about your boss, der Fuhrer?
我想他正在等着夺过去
I thought he was waiting to take possession.
别急
All in good time.
等我说完
When I am finished with it.
琼斯  你知道法柜是什么吗？
Jones, do you realize what the Ark is?
是通话器
It's a transmitter.
是和上帝通话的无线电
It's a radio for speaking to God.
而现在在我手上
And it's within my reach.
你想和上帝通话吗？
You want to talk to God?
让我们一起去见他
Let's go see Him together.
我没有什么好选择的了
I've got nothing better to do.
印第叔叔  快点回家
Uncle Indy, come back home now!
印第叔叔!
Uncle Indy!
印第安纳·琼斯
Next time, Indiana Jones,
下次需要找更多的孩子来救你
it'll take more than children to save you.
印第叔叔
Uncle Indy!
我想你会在这里
I thought I would find you there.
比美国水兵还好  对吧？
Better than the United States Marines, eh?
玛丽安死了
Marion's dead.
- 是的  我知道  - 还有我! 还有我!
- Yes, I know.  -  And me! And me!
我很难过
I'm sorry.
印第  生活还得继续
Life goes on, Indy.
这里有证据
There is the proof.
我有很多事要告诉你
I have much to tell you.
首先我们先带他们回家
First we will take them home,
然后我会带你去这个老人那里
and then I will take you to the old man.
我想不出拜尔劳库怎么做到的
I can't figure out how Belloq did it.
他从哪里弄到头盔的复制品？
Where'd he get a copy of the headpiece?
没有图片  也没有复制品
There are no pictures, no duplicates of it anywhere.
我告诉你的只是我亲眼所见到的
I tell you only what I saw with my own eyes:
就象那个头盔
A headpiece like that one,
只有四周的边比较粗
except round the edges, which were rougher.
那个法国人在中心也嵌了水晶
In the center, the Frenchman had embedded a crystal,
还有…  水晶周围的一边
and... and surrounding the crystal, on one side,
有突起的标志  和那个一样
there were raised markings, just like that one.
他们在这个地图室做计算
They made their calculations in the map room?
今天早上
This morning.
拜尔劳库和他的德国老板
Belloq and the boss German, Dietrich.
从地图室出来后
When they came out of the map room,
就叫我们在一处新的地方挖掘
they gave us a new spot in which to dig,
离营帐很远
out away from the camp.
灵井？
The Well of the Souls, huh?
过来  过来  看  看这里…  看
Come, come, look. Look here... Look.
坐下
Sit down.
过来  坐下
Come, sit down.
这是什么？
What is it?
这是一个警告
This is a warning
警告我们不要打扰法柜
not to disturb the Ark of the Covenant.
这个杖子的高度怎么样？
What about the height of the staff, though?
拜尔劳库从这里弄到的？
Did Belloq get it off of here?
是的  就是这里
Yes. It is here.
这是个老办法
This were the old way,
这表示六卡达姆高
this mean six kadam high.
- 大约72英寸  - 等等!
- About 72 inches. -  Wait!
减去1卡达姆
"And take back one kadam
向希伯来神致敬
to honor the Hebrew God whose Ark this is."
你说他们的头饰只有一边有标记
You said their headpiece only had markings on one side.
你确定吗？
Are you absolutely sure?
拜尔劳库的权杖太长了
Belloq's staff is too long.
他们挖错地方了
They're digging in the wrong place.
我是海洋的君主
I am the monarch of the sea
我是统治…
I am the ruler of the...
枣子坏了
Bad dates.
我告诉过你不要太早给柏林公报
I told you not to be premature in your communique to Berlin.
考古学不是严密的科学
Archeology is not an exact science.
不能按时间表
It does not deal in time schedules.
元首没耐心
The Fuhrer is not a patient man.
他要求经常报告  他要进展
He demands constant reports, and he expects progress.
你使我相信…
You led me to believe...
我没许诺过什么
Nothing! I made no promises.
我只说情况良好
I only said it looked very favorable.
照我们的资料
Besides, with the information in our possession,
我们计算得不错
my calculations were correct.
他们不是开玩笑吧？
Boy, they're not kidding, are they?
阳光什么时候照进地图室？
What time does the sun hit the map room?
大约早上9点
At about 9:00 in the morning.
没多少时间了
Not much time, then.
他们在哪里挖灵井？
Where are they digging for the Well of the Souls?
在那条沟上…  但地图室在那边
On that ridge... but the map room's over there.
我们走吧
Let's go, come on.
萨拉
Sallah.
Sallah!
他们在这里
They're here.
朋友  什么事？
Please, my friend, what is the matter?
哦  还要水？我去给你拿
I fetch the water. I shall get it for you.
如果你要水  我就给你水
If you want water, I will get you water.
不要紧  不要紧
No problem, no problem.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
他们一定换了篮子
You must have switched baskets.
你受伤没有？
Are you hurt?
没有  你一定要尽快把我弄出去
No. You have to get me out of here, quick.
他们随时都可能回来
They're gonna be back at any minute.
给我割开
Cut me loose.
快
Quick.
他们一直问起你知道些什么
They keep asking about you. What you know.
怎么回事？
What's wrong?
给我松绑
Cut me loose.
玛丽安  我知道法柜在哪里了!
I know where the Ark is, Marion.
法柜在这里？
The Ark's here?
我跟你一起去  琼斯  让我出去
I'm coming with you, Jones. Get me out of here!
给我松绑  带我离开这里!
Cut me loose! You can't leave me here!
如果现在我带你离开这里
If I take you out of here now,
他们会到处找我们的
they'll start combing the place for us.
你必须放我出去!
Jones, you've got to get me out of here!
快  琼斯  你疯了吗？
Come on, Jones, are you crazy?
玛丽安  我不想这样做
Marion, I hate to do this,
如果你还不坐下并保持安静的话
but if you don't sit still and keep quiet,
整件事就砸了
this whole thing is going to be shot.
我会回来救你的
I'll be back to get you.
琼斯  怎么回事？
Jones, what's the matter?
就是这个
That's it.
谁知道？
Who knows?
也许法柜仍然在某处
Perhaps the Ark is still waiting
等着我们去找到它
in some antechamber for us to discover.
也许有重要的证据  我们还没有注意到
Perhaps there's some vital bit of evidence which eludes us.
- 有可能…  - 也许这个女孩能帮助我们
- Perhaps... -  Perhaps the girl can help us.
我的感觉是对的
My feeling exactly.
她持有原件许多年
She was in possession of the original piece for years.
如果有适当的理由  她可能知道更多
She may know much, if properly motivated.
告诉你  这个女孩什么都不知道
I tell you, the girl knows nothing.
我很惊讶你的拘谨
I'm surprised to find you squeamish.
这不是你的风格
That is not your reputation.
不过你不必管这些
But it needn't concern you.
我有最佳的人选干这事
I have the perfect man for this kind of work.
嗨  希特勒!
Heil Hitler.
印第!  在这里!
Indy! Here!
我们碰上了石头!
We've hit stone!
把它清理出来
Clear it off.
快点  找到边
Come on, find the edges.
不错  不错  不错
Good, good, good.
印第  你看见了吗？
You see, Indy? You see?
好  把撬杠拿过来
Okay, bring the pry bars in.
大家一起用力!  用力!
As a team, boys! As a team!
推!
Push!
把它弄到这里来  下面
Get 'em in there. Get 'em under.
好的  好的  就是这个
Good, good, that's it.
小心脚趾!
Watch your toes.
小心  小心!
Carefully, carefully!
对不起  印第
Sorry, Indy.
印第…
Indy...
地板为什么会动？
why does the floor move?
把火把给我
Give me your torch.
蛇
Snakes.
为什么有蛇呢？
Why did it have to be snakes?
毒蛇
Asps.
很危险
Very dangerous.
你先下去
You go first.
你如果想徒步逃跑
If you're trying to escape on foot,
无论从哪个方向  都要在沙漠中走三个星期
the desert is three weeks in every direction,
所以吃点东西吧
so please, eat something.
我必须为他们这样对你而道歉
I must apologize for their treatment of you.
嗯  谁的主意？
Yeah. Whose idea was it?
没有食物  没有水
No food, no water.
你的这些朋友是什么人？
What kind of people are these friends of yours?
在这个特殊的时刻和地点  为了完成我的工作
At this particular time and place, to do my work,
需要他们这些坏人
they are necessary evils.
他们不是我的朋友
They're not my friends.
然而  只要有正常的联系
However, with the right connections,
即使是在这个偏僻的角落
even in this part of the world,
我们也不完全是野蛮人
we are not entirely uncivilized.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
我很希望你加入
I would very much like to see you in it.
当然!
I'll bet you would.
好的
All right.
你这里有什么喝的？
What do you got to drink around here?
我们没什么时间了
We don't have much time.
他们就要来伤害你了
Soon they will come to harm you,
对此我无能为力
and I will not be able to stop them,
除非你给我点东西
unless you are able to give me something
安抚他们
to placate them.
嗯  一些情报…
Some, uh, piece of information...
我可以用来保护你
which I can use to protect you from them.
我已经把知道的全告诉你了
I've already told you everything I know.
我没有必要为琼斯卖命
I have no loyalty to Jones.
他给我带来的只有麻烦
He's brought me nothing but trouble.
玛丽安  你真美
Marion, you are beautiful.
我想我们不需要人看着
I don't think we need a chaperone.
不要急!
Steadily.
慢慢来  哇!
Steadily. Whoa!
下去…
Down...
再下去
Down... Whoa.
小心  小心!
Carefully, carefully!
还好吧  印第？
You all right, Indy?
轻点  轻点!
Now gently, boys. Gently, gently!
哇…
Whoa...
我说过没事
I told you it will be all right.
萨拉  下来!
Sallah, get down here!
你倒酒!
You pour.
太棒了
Oh, that's good.
哎哟
Whoops.
这东西是什么  雷内？
What is this stuff, Rene?
我从小就喝这个
I grew up with this.
这是我家的家徽
It's my family label.
好了…  我要走了  雷内
Well... I have to be going now, Rene.
我喜欢你  雷内
I like you, Rene, very much.
也许我们会在更好的地方后会有期
Perhaps we'll meet someday under better circumstances.
小姐  我们又见面了
We meet again, Freulein.
你们美国人都一样
You Americans, you're all the same.
总在不适合的场合打扮
Always overdressing for the wrong occasions.
现在…
Now...
我们谈些什么呢？
what shall we talk about?
好的…拉上去
All right... take it up!
放轻松!
Easy!
你像那个女孩一样倔强
You're as stubborn as that girl.
我想你太喜欢她了
You like her too much, I think.
你的考古法太原始了
Your methods of archeology are too primitive for me.
你会用台压路机找个… 中国小杯子
You would use a bulldozer to find a... china cup.
斯雷曼!  把你的人叫醒!
Colonel! Wake your men!
印第  火把快灭了
Indy, the torches are burning out.
离开这里吧
Go on, get out of here.
- 萨拉!   - 喂!
- Sallah! -  Hello!
喂!
Hello!
琼斯博士 你在这个脏地方干什么？
Why, Dr. Jones, whatever are you doing in such a nasty place?
为什么你不下来呢？你下来我就给你看!
Why don't you come on down here! I'll show you!
谢了  朋友
Thank you, my friend,
不过我想我们呆在上面很舒服
but I think we are all very comfortable up here.
是不是？
That's right, isn't it?
是的  我们在上面很舒服
Yes, we are very comfortable up here.
又一次  琼斯
So, once again, Jones,
曾经短暂的属于你  现在是我的了
what was briefly yours is now mine.
你一生的努力就为此
What a fitting end to your life's pursuits.
你就要成为以后被考古发掘的东西了
You're about to become a permanent addition to this archeological find.
谁知道？
Who knows?
千年以后  你可能也会很值钱
In a thousand years, even you may be worth something.
狗杂种
Son of a bitch.
琼斯博士  我想我们该走了
I'm afraid we must be going now, Dr. Jones.
柏林已经等着奖励我们了
Our prize is awaited in Berlin.
但我不想留下你一个人在这种可怕的地方
But I do not wish to leave you down in that awful place all alone.
你这个猪  放开我
Slimy pig, you let me go!
住手!
Stop it!
玛丽安!
Marion!
抓住
Hang on.
别…
Don't...
- 印第!   - 不要摔下来
- Indy!    -  Don't fall!
玛丽安  我接住你  我接住你!
Marion, I got you! I got you! I got you!
你这个叛徒  别碰我!
You traitor! You get your hands off of me!
蛇!
Snakes!
当心你的脚下
Oh, sh... oh, at your feet!
那女的是我的
The girl was mine!
她对我们没什么用了
She's of no use to us.
完成元首的使命要紧
Only our mission for the Fuhrer matters.
我想有时你思想中没有明确这一点
I wonder sometimes, monsieur, if you have that clearly in mind.
亲爱的  没办法了
It was not to be, cherie.
你们这些王八蛋  我会报仇的
You bastards! I'll get you for this!
印第安纳·琼斯…
Indiana Jones...
再见
adieu.
不!
No!
拿着这个
Take this.
向任何滑动的东西摇晃它
Wave it at anything that slithers.
谢谢
Thank you.
上帝  这里到处都是滑溜溜的
Oh, my God, this whole place is slithering.
印第!
Indy!
哎哟  天哪!
Ow! Jesus!
这个你是从哪里得到的？从他那儿？
Where did you get this? From him?
我想逃跑
I was trying to escape.
你没帮我
No thanks to you.
你尽了多大努力？
How hard were you trying?
你那时在哪里？
Well, where the hell were you?
看着  看着
Watch it, watch it.
- 你干什么？ - 这个可以增强火势
- What are you doing?   -  For the fire!
我们怎么出去？
How the hell are we going to get out of here?
我正在想办法!
I'm working on it! I'm working on it!
不管你做什么  你得快点
Well, whatever you're doing, do it faster.
啊…
Ah...
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
穿过这堵墙
Through that wall.
准备快跑  不要管我
Just get ready to run, whatever happens to me.
什么意思？
What do you mean by that?
印第!
Indy!
该死!  别让我一个人留在这里!
Damn it! Don't you leave me down here by myself!
印第!
Indy!
来啦
Here we go!
准备好!
Get ready!
印第  火把要灭了!
Indy, the torch is going out!
印第？
Indy?
玛丽安!
Marion!
看  看
Look. Look.
他们想用飞机把它运走
They're going to fly it out of here.
等把法柜装上
When that Ark gets loaded,
我们就在飞机上了
we're already going to be on the plane.
先生 让我们来祝贺沙漠中的胜利
Ah, monsieur, let us toast our success in the desert.
为法柜干杯
To the Ark.
当我们远离这里的时候
When we are very far from here.
再庆祝吧
That Will do.
嗨  来这里!
Hey, you now... Come here!
这里!
Come here!
印第!
Indy!
守着法柜!  守着法柜!
Stay with the Ark! Stay with the Ark!
小心!
Look out!
哦  天呐
Oh, my God.
玛丽安
Marion.
这里!  上来
In here! Up here!
印第  快!
Indy, come on!
拉闩锁
Pull on the latch!
它开始上升了!
Move up! It's gonna blow up!
它被粘住了!  印第!
It's stuck! Indy!
这东西脱不开!
I can't force the lock!
它被粘住了!
It's stuck!
- 转动它  - 不能动了
- Turn it! Turn it!   -  It's stuck!
转动它!
Turn it there!
没关系!  往后退!  往后退!
Never mind! Get back! Get back!
马上把法柜带走
Get the Ark away from this place immediately.
把它放上卡车
Have it put on the truck.
我们马上飞离开罗
We'll fly it out of Cairo.
高伯尔  我需要足够的保护
And Gobler, I want plenty of protection.
琼斯
Jones.
朋友们
Holy smoke, my friends,
我…我真高兴你们没死
I... I'm so pleased you're not dead!
印第  我们没时间了
Indy, Indy, we have no time.
如果你还想要法柜
If you still want the Ark,
它正被装上卡车运往开罗
it is being loaded onto a truck for Cairo.
卡车？
Truck?
什么卡车？
What truck?
走!
Let's go!
回开罗
Get back to Cairo.
给我们找些英国的交通工具
Get us some transport to England...
船  飞机  什么都行
boat, plane, anything.
在奥马尔家和我见面  帮我准备
Meet me at Omar's. Be ready for me.
我去追卡车
I'm going after that truck.
- 怎么追？ - 我也不知道
- How?    -  I don't know.
一路追一路想
I'm making this up as I go.
他在那儿
He's there!
白痴!  真是白痴!
Idiot! Idiot!
一切都安排好了
Everything at last has been arranged.
- 法柜呢？ - 在船上了
- The Ark?   -  Is on board.
你们来了  什么都齐了
Nothing is lacking, now that you're here.
你左边的是谁？
Or what is left of you.
- 你相信这些家伙么？ - 是的
- You trust these guys?   -  Yes.
卡坦嘎先生
Mr. Katanga.
卡坦嘎先生  这些是我的朋友
Mr. Katanga, these are my friends.
他们是我的家人
They are my family.
如果不好好待他们  我会知道的
I will hear of it if they are not treated well.
我的船是他们的
My cabin is theirs.
琼斯先生…
Mr. Jones...
我听过你很多事
I've heard a lot about you, sir.
你的模样跟我想的正一样
Your appearance is exactly the way I imagined.
再见
Good-bye.
保重
Look after each other.
我已经开始想你了
I am already missing you.
你是我的好朋友
You're my good friend.
萨拉
Sallah.
这是给菲雅…
That is for Fayah...
这是给孩子们的…
that is for your children...
这是给你的
and this is for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
英国空军令人敬畏
A British tar is a soaring soul
就像山上的鸟儿那样自由自在
As free as a mountain bird
他应该准备好铁拳…
His energetic fist should be ready to...
…对付独裁者…
...a dictator...
你去哪里了？
Where did you go?
我在洗脸
I'm cleaning up.
你的睡衣哪里来的？
Where'd you get that?
从他那
From him.
谁？
Who him?
卡坦嘎
Katanga.
我感觉这船上有别的女人
I got a feeling I'm not the first woman
和这些海盗一起航行
ever to travel with these pirates.
很可爱
It's lovely.
是吗？
Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
真的？
Really?
真的
Yeah.
你说什么？
What'd you say?
慢点…我不需要任何帮助
Wait... I don't need any help.
你知道你要的
You know you do.
你和十年前我认识的你不一样了
You're not the man I knew ten years ago.
这不是年龄的关系  这是一段一段经历
It's not the years, honey, it's the mileage.
你是…
You are...
我不需要看护
Please, I don't need a nurse.
- 我只想睡一下   - 别象个小孩一样
- I just want to sleep.    -  Don't be such a baby.
玛丽安  让我一个人待着
Marion, leave me alone.
- 这是什么？ - 走开
- What is this here?   -  Go away.
是的  疼
Yes, it hurts.
哎哟!
Ow!
该死  印第  到底哪儿不痛？
Well, goddamn it, Indy, where doesn't it hurt?
这里
Here.
这还不太坏
This isn't too bad.
这里
Here.
琼斯…
Jones...
琼斯？
Jones?
我们好象从来没有歇过
We never seem to get a break, do we?
什么事？
What is it?
引擎停了  我去检查一下
Engines have stopped. I'm going to go check.
- 什么事？ - 我们有些最重要的朋友
- What's happening? -  We have most important friends.
妈的
Holy shit.
我派人找你  你和那个女孩必须躲起来
I sent my man for you. You and the girl must disappear.
我们有个地方  快点  去
We have a place in the hold. Come on, go, go, go.
快  朋友  快去
Come on, go, my friend, go.
琼斯博士在哪里？
Where is Dr. Jones?
什么事这么重要？
What's the big idea?
放开我!
Let go!
不要碰我
Don't you touch me.
琼斯呢？
What about Jones?
没有他的行踪
There's no trace yet, sir.
琼斯死了
Jones is dead.
我杀了他
I killed him.
他对我们没有用处了
He was of no use to us.
但这个女的对我们要去的地方有特别的用处
This girl, however, has certain value where we're headed.
能卖个好价钱
She'll bring a very good price.
嗯？
Mmm?
上校先生  这是你的货
Herr Colonel, that cargo you've taken...
你要就拿去
If it's your goal, go in peace with it,
把这女的留给我们
but leave us the girl.
这多少会减少我们这趟旅行的损失
It would reduce our loss on this trip.
野蛮人!
Savage!
你没资格要求什么
You are not in the position to ask for anything.
我们要拿什么就拿什么
We will take what we wish.
然后再决定是否炸了你的船
And then decide whether or not to blow your ship from the water.
这个女的跟我走
The girl goes with me.
她可以作为我的部分补偿
She'll be part of my compensation.
我想你们的元首会同意的
I'm sure your Fuhrer would approve.
如果她不能令我满意
If she fails to please me,
可任你处置
you may do with her as you wish.
我不会再在她身上浪费时间了
I will waste no more time with her now.
对不起
Excuse me.
船长  我找不到琼斯博士
I can't find Mr. Jones, Captain.
我已经到处找过了
I've looked everywhere.
他一定在这里某个地方
He's got to be here somewhere.
再找找
Look again.
- 我找到他了  - 哪儿？
- I found him.   -  Where?
那儿
There.
根据你的无线电指示
The altar has been prepared in accordance
祭坛已经准备好了
with your radio instructions, sir.
很好
Good.
把法柜马上送去
Take the Ark there immediately.
先生…
Monsieur...
我有点不舒服  因为想起这个犹太人的宗教仪式
I am uncomfortable with the thought of this Jewish ritual.
你确信这是必需的吗？
Are you sure it's necessary?
让我问问你
Let me ask you this:
到柏林再打开这个法柜是否更妥当一点？
Would you be more comfortable opening the Ark in Berlin,
为了你的元首？
for your Fuhrer?
查明圣约的碎片是否在里面
Finding out, only then, if the sacred pieces of the Covenant are inside?
只有那时才知道我们是否完成了任务
Knowing, only then, whether you have accomplished your mission,
是否拿到了真正的法柜
and obtained the one true Ark?
喂!
Hello!
琼斯
Jones.
琼斯!
Jones!
我要炸了这个法柜  雷内
I'm going to blow up the Ark, Rene.
你的顽固甚至使我惊讶
Your persistence surprises even me.
你败坏了外国雇佣兵的名誉
You're going to give mercenaries a bad name.
琼斯博士…
Dr. Jones...
你当然不会以为你能逃出这个岛
surely you don't think you can escape from this island.
那要看我们是不是都愿意讲理？
That depends on how reasonable we're all willing to be.
我只要这个女的
All I want is the girl.
如果我们拒绝呢？
If we refuse?
那么你们元首也就得不到战利品
Then your Fuhrer has no prize.
好  大家往后站
Okay, stand back.
大家都往后站
All of you, stand back.
后退
Stand back.
好的  琼斯
Okay, Jones.
你赢了!
You win!
炸吧
Blow it up.
炸吧!
Yes, blow it up!
炸还给上帝
Blow it back to God.
你穷极一生都在寻找考古文物
All your life has been spent in pursuit of archeological relics.
法柜是最稀有的
Inside the Ark are treasures beyond your wildest aspirations.
你我都愿意打开来看看
You want to see it open as well as I.
印第安纳…
Indiana...
我们只是历史过客
we are simply passing through history.
这个…
This...
这就是历史
This is history.
随你便
Do as you will.
玛丽安  不要看它
Marion, don't look at it.
闭上眼睛  玛丽安
Shut your eyes, Marion.
不要看  不管发生什么事
Don't look at it, no matter what happens.
啊…
Ah...
太美了!
It's beautiful!
印第？
Indy?
不要看  玛丽安!
Don't look, Marion!
闭上眼睛!
Keep your eyes shut!
玛丽安
Marion.
感谢你为国家立了大功
You've done your country a great service, and we thank you.
我们相信你对这样解决很满意
And we trust you found the settlement satisfactory.
钱倒不少
Oh, the money's fine.
情况完全不行
The situation's totally unacceptable.
先生们  这和我想的差不多
Well, gentlemen, I guess that just about wraps it up.
法柜在哪里？
Where is the Ark?
我们已经放好它了
I thought we'd settled that.
法柜在一个很安全的地方
The Ark is somewhere very safe.
为了防谁？
From whom?
法柜有神奇的力量
The Ark is a source of unspeakable power
必须研究
and it has to be researched.
会的  我向你保证  布鲁迪博士
And it will be, I assure you, Dr. Brody,
琼斯博士
Dr. Jones.
我们现在有高级人员在研究
We have top men working on it right now.
谁？
Who?
高级人员
Top men.
嗨  怎么了？
Hey, what happened?
你好像不高兴
You don't look very happy.
- 这些官僚笨蛋   - 他们说什么？
- Fools. Bureaucratic fools.   -  What'd they say?
他们不知道那是什么东西
They don't know what they've got there.
我知道我这里有什么
Well, I know what I've got here.
来吧
Come on.
我请你喝一杯
I'll buy you a drink.
喝一杯？
You know...a drink?